Register of the Karl August Wittfogel papers, 1728-1992
Hoover Institution Archives
- SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, 1913-1990
  - "Russia and the East: A Comparison and Contrast," Slavic Review, 1963 December
    - Typescript (Folder 7)
    - Printed copy. Includes KAW's reply to Nicholas V. Riasanovsky and Bertold Spuler, whose articles were published in the same issue of Slavic Review (Folder 8)
  - "Some Remarks on Mao's Handling of Concepts and Problems of Dialectics," Studies in Soviet Thought, 1963 December. Printed copies (Folder 9)
  - Five entries for the Dictionary of Political Science ("Mao Tse-tung," "Oriental Despotism," "Law of Diminishing Administrative Returns," "Multicentered Societies," and "Singlecentered Societies"), 1964. Typescripts. Includes two entries not published ("Power Economy and Subsistence Economy" and "Beggars' Democracy") (Folder 10)
  - Contribution to television series on the subject of communism, Institute on the Nature of Communism, Vanderbilt University, Nashville, Tennessee, 1964. Typescript outlines or transcripts
    - General (Folder 11)
    - "The Sino-Soviet Conflict" (unnumbered) (Folder 12)
    - "Mao Tse-tung's Ideological Contributions (No. 20) (Folder 13)
    - "Agriculture and the Peasants" (No. 30) (Folder 14)
    - "The Chinese Communist Struggle for Power" (No.37) (Folder 15)
    - "The Chinese Communist Regime" (No. 38) (Folder 16)
  - Speech, Institute of International Studies, University of South Carolina, Columbia, South Carolina, 1964 March 24? Clipping (Folder 17)
  - "Problems of the Sino-Soviet Conflict," 1964 April 7. Speech, University of Minnesota, Minneapolis, Minnesota. Clipping (Folder 18)
  - Speech, Asian Studies Series, University of Chattanooga, Tennessee, 1964 June 5. Clipping (Folder 19)
  - "State, Society, and Development," 1965? Speech at the University of Notre Dame? Typescript (Folder 20)
  - "Agriculture and the Peasant: The Foundation of Traditional China and the Achilles Heel of Chinese Communism," 1965 May 6. Typescript outline (Folder 21)
  - "The Real Issues Involved in the Study of Oriental Despotism" (originally intended for the second French edition of Oriental Despotism), 1965 August. Typescript
    - July (Folder 22-24)
    - July-August (Box 92., Folder 1-2)
  - Review of Etienne Balazs, Chinese Civilization and Bureaucracy: Variation on a Theme, in Annals of the American Academy of Political and Social Science, 1965 November. Typescript. Includes obituary of Etienne Balazs by P. Demieville, annotated by KAW (Folder 3)
  - "The West and Oriental Despotism," 1965 December
    - Bibliographic index cards (Folder 4)
    - Notes and outline (Folder 5-7)
    - Holograph (Folder 8)
    - Typescript
      - August-September (Folder 9)
      - October-December (Folder 10-11)
      - November-December (Folder 12)
      - December 31 (partial) (Folder 13)
  - Lettre au Lecteur, 1966. See Oriental Despotism, 1957, French translation
  - Memoirs, 1966. Oral history project conducted by Gary L. Ulmen. See also AUDIO-VISUAL FILE, Phonotapes
    - General (Box 93., Folder 1)
    - Typed transcript of recordings
      - Copy A
        - Tapes 1-17 (Folder 2-18)
        - Tapes 18-29 (Box 94., Folder 1-12)
      - Copy B
        - Tapes 1-5 (Folder 13-17)
        - Tapes 6-23 (Box 95., Folder 1-18)
        - Tapes 24-29 (Box 96., Folder 1-6)
      - Copy C
        - Tapes 1-11 (Folder 7-17)
        - Tapes 12-29 (Box 97., Folder 1-18)
        - Fragments of Tapes 9 and 10 (Folder 19)
  - "Recent Developments in the Discussion of the 'Asiatic Mode of Production' and Oriental Despotism," 1966 April 28. Comments on the occasion of the publication of the French edition of Oriental Despotism, Modern Chinese History Project Colloquium, University of Washington, Seattle, Washington. Typescript (Box 98., Folder 1)
  - Speech? University of Washington, Seattle, Washington, 1966 May 10? Clipping (Folder 2)
  - "World History and Oriental Despotism," 1966 May 26. Notes (Folder 3)
  - "Miss Roper's Guided Tour," Bulletin (Sydney, Australia), 1966 August 27. Review of Myra Roper, China: The Surprising Country
    - Typescript (Folder 4)
    - Printed copies (Folder 5)
  - "The Role of Institutions in History," 1967. Typescript outline and bibliography (Folder 6)
  - "The Chinese Red Guards and the 'Lin Piao Line,'" AFL-CIO Free Trade Union News, 1967 January-February
    - Typescript (Folder 7)
    - Printed copies (Folder 8)
    - French translation. Printed copy (Folder 9)
    - German translation. Printed copy (Folder 10)
    - Italian translation. Printed copy (Folder 11)
  - Review of Robert McC. Adams, The Evolution of Urban Society: Early Mesopotamia and Prehispanic Mexico, in American Anthropologist, 1967 February. Printed copy (Folder 12)
  - Foreword to Chu Tung-tsu, Han Social Structure, 1967 March. Typescript (Folder 13)
  - "Results and Problems of the Study of Oriental Despotism," 1967 August 13. Speech, 27th International Congress of Orientalists, Ann Arbor, Michigan
    - General (Folder 14)
    - Holograph (in part typescript) (Folder 15)
    - Typescript. Includes abstract (Folder 16-19)
    - Proofs (Folder 20)
    - Printed copy (Folder 21)
    - Spanish translation. Printed copy (Folder 22)
  - "Communist and Non-Communist Agrarian Systems, With Special Reference to the USSR and Communist China: A Comparative Approach," 1967 August 23. Paper, Far Eastern and Russian Institute, University of Washington, Seattle, Washington. See also CORRESPONDENCE, Jackson, W. A. Douglas
    - General (Box 99., Folder 1)
    - Notes and typescript (Folder 2)
  - "The Theory of 'Oriental' Society, 'Hydraulic' Society, and 'Managerial' Society," 1967 September 6. Speech, Escuela, Mexico. Notes (Folder 3)
  - Notes, 1968 March 7 (written on a paper napkin at Green Apple Restaurant, New York City) (Folder 4)
  - "Memorandum on Comparative Studies of Total Power," 1968 June 3. Typescript. Includes cover letter to the Lilly Endowment (Folder 5)
  - "Some Remarks on Total and Partial Alienation in the Academic Community," 1969 March 29-30. Memorandum prepared for a meeting of the National Committee of the National Council of Scholars, Washington, D.C.
    - Typescript (in part holograph) (Folder 6)
    - Correspondence with Will Herberg, Robert Morris, Gerhart Niemeyer, David N. Rowe, 1968-1969 (Folder 7)
    - Memoranda, minutes, and reports, 1968-1969, relating mainly to the meetings of the Sub-Committee on Academic Alienation. Includes a preliminary report on 'Academic Alienation' by Gerhart Niemeyer (Folder 8)
  - "Marxism, Anarchism, and the New Left," 1969 September 3. Paper, American Political Science Association, New York City
    - General (Folder 9)
    - Notes (Folder 10)
    - Typescript. Includes abstract (Folder 11)
    - Proofs (Folder 12)
    - Printed copy (Folder 13)
  - Speech, Joint meeting of the Yeshiva and Stern College political science clubs, Yeshiva College, New York City, New York, 1969 November 6. Clipping (Folder 14)
  - Speech, University of South Carolina, Columbia, South Carolina, 1969 November 11. Clipping (Folder 15)
  - "Agriculture: A Key to the Understanding of Chinese Society, Past and Present," 1970. The Thirty-First George Ernest Morrison Lecture in Ethnology, Australian National University, Canberra, Australia
    - General (Folder 16)
    - Typescript (Folder 17)
    - Printed copy and review (Folder 18)
  - "Social Revolution in China," 1970 April 8. Speech in a series of lectures by others entitled "A World in Revolution," The University Lectures 1970, Australian National University, Canberra, Australia
    - General (Folder 19)
    - Typescript (Folder 20)
    - Printed copy (Folder 21)
    - Expanded version (part two of "The Nationalist Versus the Communist Revolution in China, With Special Reference to Marx' View of Social Revolution in Asia," 1972 June) (Folder 22)
    - Slightly edited version published in The Alternative, 1973 December (Folder 23)
    - Italian translation. Printed copy (Folder 24)
  - "Comments on Dr. Adolph J. Ackerman's paper," IEEE Transactions on Aerospace and Electronic Systems, 1970 December 2
    - Typescript (Box 100, Folder 1)
    - Printed copy (Folder 2)
  - "Irrigation Policy in Spain and Spanish America," in A. R. Desai, ed., Essays on Modernization of Underdeveloped Societies, 1971
    - Typescript (Folder 3)
    - Printed copy (Folder 4)
  - "Ecology and the Development of Society," 1971 April 29. Speech, State University of New York, Stony Brook, New York
    - General (Folder 5)
    - Notes (Folder 6)
  - "The Classical View of Asian History and Society," 1971 December 29. Speech, Eighteenth Annual Luncheon, Conference on Asian History, American Historical Association, New York City
    - Notes (Folder 7)
    - Typescript (Folder 8)
    - Correspondence with Sidney D. Brown, Grant K. Goodman, James E. Sheridan, and C. Martin Wilbur, 1971-1972. Includes introduction of KAW by Grant K. Goodman (Folder 9)
  - "The Hydraulic Approach to Pre-Spanish Mesoamerica," in Richard S. MacNeish, Frederick Johnson et al., editors, The Prehistory of the Tehuacan Valley, vol. 4, Chronology and Irrigation, 1972
    - Notes (Folder 10)
    - Typescript (Folder 11)
    - Printed copy (Folder 12)
  - "How Happy Are the Peasants?" National Review, 1972 March 3. Printed copy (Folder 13)
  - "Three Steps in the Critical Rejection of the Communist Revolution and Society," 1972 March 28. Typescript (Folder 14)
  - "Reflections on Stalinism and the Hydraulic Society," 1972 April 12. Speech, University Seminar on Communism, Columbia University, New York City. Notes and typescript account (Folder 15)
  - "Seven Aspects of Oriental Society and 'Asiatic' Despotism," 1972 July 19. Notes (Folder 16)
  - "Problems of Marxism and Relations Between the East and the West," 1973 November 2. Paper, Twelfth Annual Central Slavic Conference, Oklahoma State University, Stillwater, Oklahoma
    - General (Folder 17)
    - Notes (Folder 18)
    - Typescript (Folder 19)
    - Proofs (Box 101, Folder 1)
    - Printed copy (Folder 2)
  - "Why We Should Study Marx," 1973 November 5. Speech, Hoover Institution on War, Revolution and Peace, Stanford, California. Notes and holograph outlines (Folder 3)
  - "Technology and Civilization: An Hydraulic Interpretation of the New and Old World," 1973 November 8. Speech, University of British Columbia, Vancouver, Canada. Clipping (Folder 4)
  - "Should We Take China Seriously?" 1976 April. Speech, Georgetown University, Washington, D.C. Clipping (Folder 5)
  - "Abstract of the Argument to be Presented in the Discussion of Richard E. Pipes' Russia Under the Old Regime," 1976 December 30. Paper, American Historical Association, Washington, D.C.
    - Notes (Folder 6)
    - Typescript (Folder 7)
    - Paper by George F. Kennan and comments by Jaroslaw Pelenski, annotated by KAW. Includes notes (Folder 8)
    - Correspondence with David M. Goldfrank, Jacob M. Price, Richard E. Pipes, and Sergius Yakobson, 1975-1976 (Folder 9)
  - "China und die osteurasische Kavallerie-Revolution: Sozial-historische Einsichten gewonnen in Begegnungen mit Karl Heinrich Menges. Ein Beitrag zu Menges' Biographie une eine Laudatio mit Fragmenten einer Autobiographie des Laudators," 1977. See also CORRESPONDENCE, Beyer, Rolf; Decsy, Gyula; Eisler-Fischer, Louise; Festschrift in Honor of Prof. Karl H. Menges; Otto Harrassowitz Verlag
    - Notes (Folder 10)
    - Typescript (Folder 11)
    - Proofs (Folder 12)
    - English translation. Typescript (Box 102, Folder 1)
  - "Hydraulic Society and Beyond," 1977 January 24. Speech, New York Academy of Sciences, Section of Anthropology, New York City
    - General (Folder 2)
    - Notes (Folder 3)
  - "The Development of Russia and Marxism," 1977 April 14. Speech in memory of Joseph Schiebel, Washington, D.C. Notes. Includes clippings regarding Joseph Schiebel (Folder 4)
  - "Gegen bestimmte Sachen muss man kampfen," 1977 October 23. Broadcast of interview by Matthias Greffrath, published along with other interviews under the title "Die hydraulische Gesellschaft und das Gespenst der asiatischen Restauration" in Die Zerstorung einer Zukunft: Gesprache mit emigrierten Sozialwissenschaftlern
    - Typescript (Folder 5)
    - Proofs (Folder 6)
    - Review of book by Gunter Maschke (Folder 7)
  - Autobiographical remarks, 1978 September. Holograph fragment (Folder 8)
  - "Vom Versagen der Linken," Zeit, 1979 March 9. Interview by Fritz J. Raddatz
    - Holograph and typescript fragments (Folder 9)
    - Proofs (Folder 10)
    - Printed copy (Folder 11)
  - "Origins of Despotism," 1979 April 18. Speech, Broward Community College, Fort Lauderdale, Florida
    - General (Folder 12)
    - Notes (Folder 13)
  - Participation with Conrad Ahlers, Rudolf Bahro, and Rudi Dutschke in discussion, "Marxist Plurality and the Stability of Communist Systems," Bildungsforum, Dusseldorf, Germany, 1979 November 14. Clippings (Folder 14)
  - "Hitler, Stalin und die Bedrohung der Freiheit," 1979 November 27. Speech, Johanneum, Luneburg, Germany. Announcement, clippings, and correspondence with A. Trebchen (Folder 15)
  - "New Studies on Marx' Interpretation of Russia," 1979 December 4. Speech, London School of Economics, London, England. Notes (Folder 16)
  - "Conversations with Wittfogel," Telos, 1980 Spring. Interviews by Matthias Greffrath, Fritz J. Raddatz, and Michel Korzec
    - Typescript (Folder 17)
    - Printed copy (Folder 18)
  - Comments on Wu Da-kun, "The Asiatic Mode of Production in History as Viewed from General Political Economy," 1981. Holograph (Folder 19)
  - Introduction to Karl Marx: Enthullungen zur Geschichte der Diplomatie im 18. Jahrhundert, 1981 (published in German, though drafted in English). See also CORRESPONDENCE, Suhrkamp Verlag
    - General. Includes a printed copy of Karl Marx, Secret Diplomatic History of the Eighteenth Century(1899) (Box 103, Folder 1)
    - Foreword by Gary L. Ulmen, "A Propos Marx and Wittfogel on Russian History, Society and Revolution." Typescript (Folder 2)
    - Notes
      - 1978 (Folder 3-4)
      - 1979-1980 (Folder 5)
    - Outlines
      - Undated (Folder 6)
      - 1980 (Folder 7)
    - Holograph and typescript fragments
      - Undated (Folder 8-17)
      - 1977 October 25 (Folder 18)
      - 1978
        - Month unknown (Box 104, Folder 1-4)
        - Month unknown (Box 105, Folder 1-3)
        - February
          - 12 (Folder 4)
          - 20 (Folder 5)
        - April
          - 14 (Folder 6)
          - 17 (Folder 7)
        - May
          - 9 (Folder 8)
          - 16 (Folder 9)
        - June
          - 1 (Folder 10)
          - 6 (Folder 11)
          - 25 (Folder 12)
        - October (Folder 13)
        - December (Folder 14)
      - 1979
        - Month unknown (Box 106, Folder 1-4)
        - Month unknown (Box 107, Folder 1-5)
        - January
          - 3-10 (Box 108, Folder 1)
          - 21 (Folder 2)
          - 21-23 (Folder 3)
        - February (Folder 4-5)
        - March
          - 6-19 (Folder 6)
          - 23 (Folder 7)
        - April (Folder 8)
        - May (Folder 9)
        - June (Folder 10)
        - August (Folder 11)
        - September (Folder 12)
        - September-October (Box 109, Folder 1)
        - October
          - 2-15 (Folder 2)
          - 24 (Folder 3)
          - 25-31 (Folder 4)
        - November (Folder 5)
      - 1980
        - Month unknown (Folder 6-10)
        - Month unknown (Box 110, Folder 1-6)
        - January 30 - February 13 (Folder 7)
        - February 7 (Folder 8)
        - March (Folder 9)
        - April (Folder 10)
        - May (Folder 11)
        - June (Box 111, Folder 1)
        - July (Folder 2-3)
    - Footnotes
      - Undated (Folder 4)
      - 1978 (Folder 5-6)
      - 1979 (Folder 7)
      - 1980 (Folder 8)
    - German translation
      - Typescript (Folder 9-12)
      - Proofs (Folder 13)
  - "Jugend, wissenschaftliche Zusammenarbeit und apokalyptische Perspektive der Menschheit," 1981. Typescript outline and first chapter (in part holograph) (Box 112, Folder 1)
  - Notes on Barbara J. Price, "Intensification and Shift in the Mode of Production: Theoretical Implications," 1981 January 9? Includes Barbara J. Price's paper, annotated by KAW (Folder 2)
  - "Von spontaner Liebe zur Heimat zur apokalyptischen Vision der russischen Erben Genghis-Khans," 1981 March 14
    - Holograph (Folder 3-4)
    - Typescript (in part holograph)
      - General (Folder 5)
      - In the form of a letter to "Millie" (Milli Klatt?), February 28 (Folder 6)
  - "The Environmental Approach to Oriental Despotism, Including Problems of Marxism," 1981 November 17. Speech, Johns Hopkins University, Baltimore, Maryland. Notes (Folder 7)
  - "Orientalische Despotie: Leben, Ideen, und Entdeckungen von Karl August Wittfogel," 1982 February 5. Television broadcast (Westdeutscher Rundfunk) of interview by Jurgen Ruhle
    - General (Folder 8)
    - Notes (Folder 9)
    - Typescript (Folder 10)
  - "The Unknown Marx Reinvoked 100 Years After His Death (March 14, 1883), 1983 March 14? " Speech, Institut fur Sozialforschung, Frankfurt, Germany. Typescript (in part holograph) (Box 113, Folder 1)
  - "Wenn die Engel schweigen, mussen die Steine schreien: Ein Besuch bei Karl August Wittfogel," 1983 May 10. Televison broadcast of interview by Wolfgang M. Schwiedrzik
    - General (Folder 2)
    - Notes (Folder 3)
    - Typescript (Folder 4)
  - "Oriental Despotism and Beyond," 1983 October 5. Speech, Columbia University, New York City
    - Notes (Folder 5)
    - Clippings (Folder 6)
  - Contribution to the catalog for the Malik Verlag exhibit, Goethe House, New York City, 1984 September 25-October 20
    - Holograph (Folder 7)
    - Proofs and printed copy of catalog (Folder 8)
    - Correspondence with James H. Fraser, Knut Heuer, and C. Wecker, 1984 (Folder 9)
  - Interview by James H. Fraser, 1985. Notes and typed transcript of tape (Folder 10)
  - "Zur Feier des Wandervogels im Rahmen der 750-Jahrfeier Berlins," 1987 August 13. Typescript statement (Folder 11)
  - "Angel Palerm's Promotion of Neo-Evolutionism at Ancient Mesoamerica and the Globe," ca. 1990. Contribution to Historia, antropologia y politica: homenaje a Angel Palerm
    - Research material (Box 114, Folder 1)
    - Notes
      - Undated (Folder 2-3)
      - 1951 and later, on Palerm's master's thesis (included) (Folder 4)
      - 1982 (Folder 5)
      - 1983 (Folder 6)
    - Outlines
      - Undated (Folder 7)
      - 1982 (Folder 8)
    - Holograph and typescript fragments
      - Undated (Folder 9-12)
      - 1981
        - Month unknown (Box 115, Folder 1-2)
        - June (Folder 3-5)
        - June-September (Folder 6)
        - July (Box 116, Folder 1)
        - August (Folder 2)
        - August-November (Folder 3)
        - September (Folder 4)
        - September-December (Folder 5)
        - October (Folder 6)
        - October-December (Folder 7)
        - November (Box 117, Folder 1)
        - November-December (Folder 2)
        - December
          - 1-11 (Folder 3)
          - 1-21 (Folder 4)
          - 21-30 (Folder 5)
          - 29-30 (Folder 6)
      - 1982
        - Month unknown (Folder 7-9)
        - January (Box 118, Folder 1)
        - February (Folder 2)
        - February-March (Folder 3)
        - February-April (Folder 4)
        - March
          - 1-16 (Folder 5)
          - 19 (Folder 6)
          - 23-29 (Folder 7)
        - April
          - 3-12 (Folder 8)
          - 3-27 (Folder 9)
          - 13-20 (Folder 10)
          - 20-29 (Folder 11)
        - April-May (Folder 12)
        - April-June (Folder 13-14)
        - May
          - 4-19 (Box 119, Folder 1)
          - 10 (Folder 2)
          - 20-31 (Folder 3)
        - June
          - 10-28 (Folder 4)
          - 30 (Folder 5)
        - June-August (Folder 6)
        - July (Folder 7)
        - July-September (Folder 8)
        - August (Folder 9)
        - September (Folder 10)
        - September-November (Folder 11)
        - October (Folder 12)
        - October-December (Folder 13)
      - 1983
        - Month unknown (Box 120, Folder 1)
        - July (Folder 2)
        - August (Folder 3)
    - Typescript, 1984
      - February 21 (final version) (Folder 4-7)
      - May 7 (corrections) (Folder 8)
    - Footnotes
      - Undated (Folder 9)
      - 1981 (Folder 10)
      - 1982 (Folder 11)
    - Spanish translation. Typescript (Folder 12)
    - Correspondence with Ernesto Dominguez Quiroga, Susana Glantz, Ernesto Meneses Morales, Victoria Miret, Mrs. Pasquale, Modesto Suarez, Carmen Viqueira, Eric R. Wolf, 1980-1986 (Folder 13)
- UNFINISHED WRITING PROJECTS, 1956-1984
  - Research material and notes for, and holograph and typescript fragments of, unidentified works
    - China (Box 121, Folder 1-27)
    - China (Box 122, Folder 1-27)
    - Marx (and others: Hegel, Engels, Saint-Simon, etc.) (Box 123, Folder 1-38)
    - Russia/Soviet Union (Box 124, Folder 1-6)
  - "The Central Problem of World History," 1974-1977
    - Outline (Folder 7)
    - Notes
      - Stalin in 1920 (Folder 8)
      - Stalin vs. China (Folder 9)
      - Stalin and Trotsky (Folder 10-12)
    - Holograph and typescript
      - 1974
        - Stalin and Trotsky (Folder 13-23)
        - Bukharin (Folder 24)
        - Kautsky and Nicolaevsky (Folder 25)
        - De Tocqueville (Box 125, Folder 1-4)
      - 1974-1975. Weber (Folder 5-9)
      - 1975-1977 (and 1974?). Marx (Box 126, Folder 1-18)
  - "China and Russia," 1961-1968
    - General (Box 127, Folder 1)
    - Original manuscript (entitled "Russia and China")
      - Notes (Folder 2-5)
      - Outline (Folder 6)
      - Typescript
        - Introduction (Two Communist Giants) (Folder 7)
        - Russia (IA1) (Folder 8)
        - China (IA2) (Folder 9)
        - Marxist View of Russia (IB1) (Folder 10)
        - Marxist View of China (IB2) (Folder 11)
        - The Russian Root Revolution and the Chinese Derivative Revolution (IIA) (Folder 12)
        - The Influence of Leninism-Stalinism in China (IIB)
          - 1961
            - November 8-December 12 (Folder 13)
            - November 17-20 (Folder 14)
            - November 21-December 6 (Folder 15)
            - November 23-December 27 (Folder 16)
            - December 8-12 (Folder 17)
          - 1961-1962
            - December 27-January 3 (Folder 18)
            - December 27-February 14. Includes part of IIC (Folder 19)
          - 1962
            - January 9-May 2 (Box 128, Folder 1)
            - January 10-May 25 (Folder 2)
            - January 14 (Folder 3)
        - The Leninist Origin of Mao's National and Peasant Policies (IIC), 1962 February 5-14 (Folder 4)
    - Final manuscript
      - Notes
        - General (Folder 5)
        - Land Reform (Folder 6-10)
      - Outlines
        - Undated (Folder 11)
        - 1966
          - February 20 (Folder 12)
          - November (Folder 13)
        - 1967
          - May 3 (Folder 14)
          - Fall (Folder 15)
      - Typescript
        - 1965 December (Folder 16-18)
        - 1965 December (Box 129, Folder 1-6)
        - 1966
          - February-March (Folder 7)
          - March (Box 130, Folder 1-3)
          - April-June (Folder 4)
        - 1966-1967 (Folder 5-9)
        - 1966-1967 (Box 131, Folder 1-11)
        - 1966-1967 (Box 132, Folder 1-18)
        - 1968 (Folder 19)
      - Bibliographical note (Folder 20)
      - Statement, 1967 May 4 (Folder 21)
  - "Chinese Communism: Collected Studies on Modern Chinese History and Society," 1956-1966. Typescript and annotated printed copies of previously published writings
    - Outline (Box 133, Folder 1)
    - Section I: Studies on the History of the Chinese Communist Party
      - Short History of Chinese Communism (Folder 2)
      - Toward the First United Front (Folder 3)
      - Toward the Second United Front (Folder 4-5)